Petri Yamamoto

Front-End Developer

Meticulous web developer with over 8 years of front end experience and passion for responsive website design and a firm believer in the mobile-first approach. W3C certified. Implemented new responsive website approach which increased mobile traffic by 20%.

- petri430yamamoto@gmail.com
- **J** 1 973 797 9183
- Singapore, Arizona
- nttps://github.com/petriyamamoto

Work Experience

HCL Singapore Pte Ltd

Front-End Developer

May 2015 - June 2018 | Remote

- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Designed and implemented web applications along with 3rd-party software integrations as a web team liaison for all inter-departmental and customer-facing projects.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Developed standard and ad hoc reports in graph format as required.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.

Citiustech

Full Stack Developer

July 2018 - March 2021 | Princeton, New Jersey, United States

- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Liaised with back end developers, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and CTO as needed.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software with complete accuracy.

Skills

Skills

- Creating web and mobile applications [1]
- Maintaining, optimizing, troubleshooting, and improving websites [2]
- Implementation of apps and landing pages from concept through deployment [3]

Libraries

- HyperText Markup Language (HTML)
- JavaScript (JS)
- Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
- JavaScript (JS) Libraries (e.g., jQuery,jQX)
- CSS Preprocessors (e.g., Sass, LESS, Stylus)
- Version Control (e.g., Git, Subversion, Mercurial)
- Responsive Design & Mobile-First Websites
- Content Management Systems (CMS)
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO)
- Microdata & Microformats
- Ruby and Ruby on Rails

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology, Computer Science

National University of Singapore

2010 - 2014 | Lower Kent Ridge Rd, Singapore 119077

Awards

- Bachelor of Information Technology
- Bachelor of Finance and Electronic Engineering